Zoo is a young woman struggling with
substance abuse, trying to turn her life
around. The problem is that she is unable
to find the courage to take responsibility
for her actions and make real change.
Zoo finds herself in debt and begins looking
for a loophole, a way to repay the debt
with money she doesn't have to work for.
She assumes since her grandmother's
passing that she could use money
from the will to pay the debt, only
to find out that her grandmother did not
leave her any money. Her grandmother
left her something else. Zoo was left with
the custody of her autistic half
sister named Music. Initially, zoo is not able
to properly care for or love music.
Their relationship is empty and troubled.
One day, in the midst of yelling and crying,
the neighbor knocked on the door
to see what was going on. Zo said to the neighbor
while sounding defeated, How
am I supposed to take care of music
when I can't even take care of myself? Day
after day, music sits in the apartment
with her headphones on, feeling alone,
even though Ziu is sitting an arm's
length away. Music is unsure what to think.
She's not ready to engage in any sort
of relationship with you because there was no
expression of devotion, care
or appreciation for her. Finally,
Tsou attempts to start loving
music. However, she does so rationally
and strategically, she attempts to check
the boxes, provide food for her, give
her toys and the opportunity to watch
TV. It is a negotiated agreement that
is a transaction of you do X and I'll
do Y, and that should equal love.
But it doesn't work. As a lyric in the movie
goes, come on, give me some Stevie
Wonder meaning, could you find the ability
to love that is not based on anything
physical, not based on a contractual
agreement. It is a feeling of love
for something that you may not
necessarily be able to see. Again, Tsou does try
to will a feeling of love upon herself
and force better behaviors into her life,
hoping that would lead to this
powerful feeling of love. But it doesn't work
in debt. And wishing she could
properly take care of music, Tsou finally breaks
down. She cries in frustration
because she is not able to connect with music.
She throws books across the room in anger
because she is unhappy with who she has
become. She wants to be better, but has
not been able to make real changes
to improve herself. Then one
afternoon, music is sitting at the kitchen table,
hyper focused on drawing Tsou
standing across the room, notices that her blue
headphones are about to fall off
while music continues to draw vigorously with
her head down, Zo walks over, bends
down and readjusts her headphones. Music looks
up, taking a break from her important
drawing. She cracks a little smile just
enough to barely show her teeth
and her eyes squint ever so slightly,
something Tsou had never seen before.
Zoo feels a warmth, a connection, an energy.
She forgets about her worries for a brief
moment. The next morning, Zoo wanted
to experience that feeling again, she woke
up 20 minutes early to make breakfast
for music, which is usually a last
minute bowl of cereal. Tsou positions the eggs
and ketchup on the plate to make the smiley
face. She then calls music to come
to the table for breakfast while
zoo washes the dishes. She looks out
the corner of her eye with curiosity
for whether music will notice the smiley face
or not. Not expecting a well-prepared
breakfast music sits down at the kitchen
table, she looks down at her plate
with curiosity and soon discovers what
she is looking at. She looks up and smiles
at Tsou, this time a full smile,
teeth showing and eyes squinting,
Zo smiled back and then that same feeling
came over her. A warmth, a connection.
Her worries vanish, a feeling of desire
to improve herself for music takes
over more and more. Zoo found the energy
and time to communicate with music, to commit
to music, to empower music, to make
music feel loved, encouraged,
wanted. At this point in the movie, Zoo says.
I'm actually learning how to love
because I love her and I'm going to continue
because now she is helping me.
Finally, Sue figured it out, the love for music
and the desire to empower music is what
energizes her to change her bad habits.
She was able to go from the person
she was to the person she wanted to be,
to the person people needed her to be.
As the lyrics go, you can't love me
unless you love you to. The idea of love
for yourself in this movie is not patting
yourself on the back, buying
yourself something new or lying to yourself
about how great you are. This love is the desire
to make life better for someone
else, and in the attempt to do so,
one must bring about the best in themselves.
In realizing the impact she was making
on music and the fact that she was improving
her own life, Tsou felt a strong
purpose and fulfillment which created more energy
to improve herself. Zoo then had the ability
to make sacrifices and withstand
change. Zoo was able to go from thinking
about making change to actually making
change. She can go from looking for a reason
to make change, to having every
reason in the world.